<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i&#39;m david</title>
    <link>http://davidomar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on i&#39;m david</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 13:03:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://davidomar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures for Subway Networks</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/writings/data-structures-for-subway-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/writings/data-structures-for-subway-networks/</guid>
      <description>Currently I&amp;rsquo;m developing a twitter bot that will share a generated subway network everyday. The first step is writing the code that will produce the network.
The first problem arised when I tried to decide how to represent it.
Originally, I only thought of generating individual lines, represented in arrays, with each element (station) containing a pair of (x, y) coordinates. But sooner than later I found problems with that approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing to Git Submodules Without Affecting Original Remote</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/writings/pushing-to-submodules-without-affecting-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 20:15:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/writings/pushing-to-submodules-without-affecting-remote/</guid>
      <description>Just today I started working with Hugo. The default way to install themes in your website is adding the theme repository as a git submodule.
Doing so, produces this structure:
-/mySite ├── .git ## Contains the git info of mySite ├── .gitmodules ## References the repositoriy added as submodule ├── themes/ ├── niceTheme/ ├── .git ## Contains the git info of niceTheme  I originally assumed there would be no problem if I modified the files inside niceTheme normally, like I did when using Jekyll themes, and then push all the changes to my repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings (again)</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/writings/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 19:48:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/writings/new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been rebooting my website at least once a year since I started it.
Originally built with WordPress, adapted to Jekyll, and then decomposed into different websites (a personal blog, and a blog about art), this particular domain was pretty much forgotten by me.
Even though it was meant to be a blog, I only used it as a landing page. The information in here eventually got outdated, and the whole project evolved into a chunk of text that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to touch out of lazyness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Generative Art @ Eventloop</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/talks/eventloop-2019-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 15:01:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/talks/eventloop-2019-09/</guid>
      <description>I presented &amp;ldquo;Generative Art: Quick introduction to start producing algorithmic visual art&amp;ldquo; at Eventloop for their September 2019 meetup.
You can see the slides and the repository that contains them.
Why? Generative Art has been increasingly interesting for me since March 2018. Although is a pretty recent interest in my life, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough experience to consider myself a reputable artist, I challenged myself to give a presentation about the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attractor Seeder</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/projects/attractor-seeder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 18:20:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/projects/attractor-seeder/</guid>
      <description>This tool was originally meant to be a personal tool to make my art production process more efficient. When I thought I may not be the only one who could take advantage of it, I decided to make it public (and better).
You can check and use the tool, or check the repository and do with its contents whatever you want.
The problem The attractors I work with are Clifford and De Jong attractors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm user stats</title>
      <link>http://davidomar.com/projects/lastfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 20:20:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidomar.com/projects/lastfm/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started scrobbling to Last.fm, I&amp;rsquo;ve been recomending it to all my friends.
I just love the idea of keeping track of what you listen, abling you to find patterns; discover your actual favorite artists, songs, and albums; and visualizing or analyzing that data with different tools available online.
Although they&amp;rsquo;re very cool, I decided that I&amp;rsquo;d like to make my own. Trying to learn several things while doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>